泰安市二零二二年初中学业水平考试
一听句子，选择适当的应答语。
每个句子读两遍。
1. How's the weather today?
2. When are you leaving for Paris?
3. What do people usually do on the Dragon Boat Festival in China?
4. you mind my opening the window?
5. Jack, it's kind of you to help me take out the rubbish.
Jack, it's kind of you to help me take out the rubbish.
二、听五段对话，选择正确答案。
每段对话读两遍。
你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读下面五个小题。
6. Is there anything wrong with my throat?
7. Is there anything wrong with my throat?
7. this is Eric Brown.
May I speak to Mr.
Smith? 8. Hello, this is Eric Brown.
Smith? 8. Mr.
my father isn't at home.
He's working in his office, and you can call him at 543 -7896.
8. look at the girl with long red hair.
She's my sister, Alice.
9. What did you do this morning?
10. What did you do this morning,
10. me, how much is a It's three dollars.
Okay, I'd like two cakes and a glass of coffee.
That'll be nine dollars.
Excuse me, how much is a cake?
It's three dollars.
Okay, I'd like two cakes and a glass of coffee.
That'll be are you going to do this afternoon, I am going to the dancing class.
听。
段对话回答第十一至十三小题。
How often do you have the class?
I usually have the class on Monday and Friday every week.
I think your life should be quite busy.
Yeah, though I'm a little tired.
I feel very happy after dancing every time.
What are you going to do this afternoon, Lily?
I am going to the dancing class.
How often do you have the class?
I usually have the class on Monday and Friday every week.
I think your life should be quite busy.
Yeah, though I'm a little tired.
I feel very happy after dancing every time.
听第二段对话，回答第十四至十六小题
Welcome to my city, Mr.
White. Thank you, Lucy.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting so long.
My train was late.
It doesn't matter.
We haven't seen each other for about ten years.
I'm so happy to see you again.
Me too. How great the changes are.
Yes, we have our own airport now, and the waiting hall can hold over 6,000 people.
That's great. I will go back to my country by plane in one week.
Welcome to my city, Mr.
White. Thank you, Lucy.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting so long.
My train was late.
It doesn't matter.
We haven't seen each other for about ten years.
I'm so happy to see you again.
Me too. How great the changes are.
Yes, we have our own airport now, and the waiting hall can hold over 6,000 people.
That's great. I will go back to my country by plane in one week.
四听短文，回答下面四个问题，选择正确答案。
短文读两遍，你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读下面四个小题。
I'm Stephen. My cousin Mike and I went to summer camp last month.
It was a wonderful camp.
The camp was near a beautiful lake.
In the camp, there were 16 boys and nine girls.
We all stayed in tents.
Mike and I slept in a tent with three other boys.
It was sunny and hot in the daytime.
The nights were windy and a little cool.
There were some interesting and useful activities for us.
We learned about the local wildlife and even learned how to catch some fish.
There were also some lessons for us to improve our English.
We listened to English stories and learned to sing some English songs after
breakfast. In the afternoon, we performed some English programs.
In the evening, we got relaxed by watching a movie.
On the last day of the 14 -day summer camp, we had a big party.
How exciting it was!
I hope I can do this again next year.
I'm Stephen. My cousin Mike and I went to summer camp last month.
It was a wonderful camp.
The camp was near a beautiful lake.
In the camp, there were 16 boys and nine girls.
We all stayed in tents.
Mike and I slept in a tent with three other boys.
It was sunny and hot in the daytime.
The nights were windy and a little cool.
There were some interesting and useful activities for us.
We learned about the local wildlife and even learned how to catch some fish.
There were also some lessons for us to improve our English.
We listened to English stories and learned to sing some English songs after
breakfast. In the afternoon, we performed some English programs.
In the evening, we got relaxed by watching a movie.
On the last day of the 14 -day summer camp, we had a big party.
How exciting it was!
I hope I can do this again next year.
五、听短文，填表格。
根据短文内容，写出下面表格中所缺信息，每空一词。
短文读三遍。
你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读表格内容。
can year. year.
Hello, boys and girls.
Can you find your way if you are in a new city?
If your answer is no, don't worry.
Here are some useful suggestions for you.
First, you can buy a map of the city.
Find out where you are on the map.
Then look for the place you're going to.
You will know how to get there easily.
Another way is to look at the sun.
The sun can help you find the directions.
For example, in the morning, the sun is in the east.
In the afternoon, the sun is in the west.
It's a good way to ask policemen.
At the traffic lights, there are usually some traffic policemen.
They will be happy to show you the way.
Taking a taxi is also a good choice.
The taxi drivers usually know the way well.
They can take you to the right place, but you may pay lots of money for it.
Of course, if you have a smartphone, you can probably find your way more quickly.
That's all. Thank you for listening.
Hello, boys and girls.
Can you find your way if you are in a new city?
If your answer is no, don't worry.
Here are some useful suggestions for you.
First, you can buy a map of the city.
Find out where you are on the map.
Then look for the place you're going to.
You will know how to get there easily.
Another way is to look at the sun.
The sun can help you find the directions.
For example, in the morning, the sun is in the east.
In the afternoon, the sun is in the west.
Next, map the Find you are in new city, find out where where That's all.
Thank you for listening.
Hello, boys and girls.
Can you find your way if you are in a new city?
If your answer is no, don't worry.
Here are some useful suggestions for you.
First, you can buy a map of the city.
Find out where you are on the map.
Then look for the place you're going to.
You will know how to get there easily.
Another way is to look at the sun.
The sun can help you find the directions.
For example, in the morning, the sun is in the east.
In the afternoon, the sun is in the west.
It's a good way to ask policemen.
At the traffic lights, there are usually some traffic policemen.
They will be happy to show you the way.
Taking a taxi is also a good choice.
The taxi drivers usually know the way well.
They can take you to the right place, but you may pay lots of money for it.
Of course, if you have a smartphone, you can probably find your way more quickly.
That's Thank you for listening.
早，
听力测试结束，请关注“锦鲤英语”微信公众号